{
    "id": "d36370a209ab4717a8f55434cf198770",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is interested  ………………………. to cook.",
            "description": "The adjective interested is followed by in + noun/-ing form. ",
            "answers": [
                "to learn",
                "to learning",
                "in learning"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t look happy ………………………….. me.",
            "description": "The adjective happy is followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "seeing",
                "to see",
                "to seeing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "That car is new, …………………………?",
            "description": "We use a negative tag after an affirmative statement.",
            "answers": [
                "is it",
                "isn't it",
                "doesn't it"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It was …………………………… that I could hardly work.",
            "description": "The structure is so + adjective/adverb + a/an + noun.",
            "answers": [
                "a so warm day",
                "so warm a day",
                "so a warm day"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They were …………………………… injured in the accident.",
            "description": "Deadly is an adjective and it means fatal. The adverb for this meaning is fatally.",
            "answers": [
                "deadly",
                "fatally",
                "deathly"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I very much enjoy …………………………….",
            "description": "The verb enjoy can be followed by a noun/pronoun/-ing form. It cannot be followed by an infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to swim",
                "swimming",
                "swim"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He would never ……………………………… if he hadn’t changed jobs.",
            "description": "The sentence is in the type three conditional. Here we use a past perfect in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the result clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have promoted",
                "have been promoted",
                "had been promoted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t trust god men. I never have, and I ……………………………..",
            "description": "The rule of parallelism. ",
            "answers": [
                "will never",
                "never will",
                "never would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was ………………………….. I was working.",
            "description": "The structure is/am/are etc. + … age is used without a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "your age",
                "at your age",
                "of your age"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Alice isn’t here today. Mary isn’t here ………………………………",
            "description": "After mentioning a negative idea or fact, we can add another negative point by using not … either.",
            "answers": [
                "either",
                "neither",
                "nor"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He often comes and …………………………… the evening with us.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "spend",
                "to spend",
                "spending",
                "spends"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "We didn’t have ……………………………. trouble going through the customs.",
            "description": "Any suggests an indefinite quantity or number. It is often used in questions and negative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "any",
                "some",
                "no",
                "enough"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}